<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Life on Dﾄ」is Vilcﾄ］s</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Life on Dﾄ」is Vilcﾄ］s</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cycling with Gerda</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/cycling-with-gerda/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/cycling-with-gerda/</guid>
      <description>Your browser does not support the video tag. Gerda is a natural born marathon runner, it is one of her favorite things to do. She can run in this pace without stopping for about 7 kilometers straight. I only pedal the bike when we have to go uphill or when the terrain gets difficult.&#xA;She behaves herself precisely like Vinny Found this video on Telegram the other day.&#xA;Your browser does not support the video tag.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chicken Steak with Pineapple Rings</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/chickensteak/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/chickensteak/</guid>
      <description>One of my hobbies is cooking, and recently I was wondering about whether there is such a thing as a chicken steak? I believe there is, and here is my interpretation.&#xA;Ingredients: Chicken breast fillet &amp;ndash; 1 kg / 2.2 lb;&#xA;A medium can of pineapple rings;&#xA;Dark soy sauce &amp;ndash; 10 tablespoons;&#xA;One large onion;&#xA;One head of garlic;&#xA;Two packs of whatever salt free chicken seasonings (~30 grams / 1 ounce)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Notes for 2024</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/2024/</guid>
      <description>Monetize a hobby; Build a couple of bicycles; Spend more time in the nature; Less perfection, more authenticity; Re-learn to write like in the old days; Listen to Radio Paradise Mellow Mix and take it easy. till next post </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Letter from Gerda</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/gerda/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2023 14:49:03 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/gerda/</guid>
      <description>Yo, what&amp;rsquo;s good to all my peeps who care &amp;lsquo;bout my destiny! It&amp;rsquo;s been a little over a year since I&amp;rsquo;ve been rollin&amp;rsquo; with this fam. Back then, rollin&amp;rsquo; into the big green yard, I was kinda scared of all that space and freedom, but my two-legged crew was all hype, encouragin&amp;rsquo; me to explore the yard.&#xA;Start was tough for all of us, filled with challenges, but they pushed me to explore, told me to trust, and every day through their actions, they showed me how wanted and loved I am.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
